WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
Coming into Survivor,
I knew it was the toughest game
you can play.
But I came into the game
to play honourably,
with loyalty and integrity.
And the title of Sole Survivor
would just be the ants pants.
People shouldn't underestimate
what a 60-year-old can do.
Oh!
She's right
in the environment she knows best.
Look at Shane go!
I'm representing
my generation.
You don't have to, you know,
warehouse yourself
and sit in a rocking chair
knitting booties.
Shane, keep doing that!
Let's not forget the fact that Shane
was a gold medallist three times
at the age of 15.
Shane Gould
is not just a champion...
Oh, jeez!
..she's a national treasure,
basically.
I'm inclined to do a...
do a blindside.
I think it's time to make moves.
I'm worried about Shonelle.
I want to get them apart.
I can outwit and outplay people.
Are you threatening me?
People better be careful, 'cause
there might be a sting in the tail.
Don't with Shane Gould.
She's so good.
She'll give it a crack.
I've given it my all
and learnt on the run
and I worked hard to find my way,
negotiate my way
through the maze of relationships.
- Three-way.
- Shh!
I came into this game as a champion.
And I'm leaving as a champion.
And it really is up there
with my other achievements.
It's really the icing on the cake.
Welcome back!
It's the Australian Survivor
Reunion Show.
Shane Gould has just been crowned
the Sole Survivor for 2018
and won $500,000.
Thanks for playing the game.
- Firstly, Shane, congratulations.
- Thank you, Jonathan.
- You're welcome.
- It was a real treat to be involved.
Yeah, really appreciate the privilege.
- So, Olympic legend.
- Mm.
Australian of the Year.
Now Sole Survivor.
How does that feel?
It feels surreal, you know?
It's been a while
since I won an Olympic medal.
Um... and it was a challenge
to see what I'm made of.
To, um... I don't know.
Just do something crazy, you know?
You know, some people
talk about swimming being, um,
not being an individual sport.
But I reflected on it a lot
and, actually, when you're swimming,
you've got to watch people
and be aware of people,
where they are next to you.
You've got to read their body language.
And I think I used that
to my advantage.
OK, so going into the final tribal,
you go up against a top barrister,
someone who
talks to a jury for a living.
How did that feel?
It was a really, really tough moment.
But I knew Sharn was, um,
very eloquent,
so I had to try and memorise,
you know, my achievements
and how I played the game.
And then when the questions started
coming, it was really difficult.
So I thought, "Oh, that's it." You
know, "Sharn's got it for sure."
It seemed to me
when you first started Survivor,
you first started on the game,
you seemed quite overwhelmed by all
of it, which I totally get.
I often feel overwhelmed too.
But as the game went on,
you really seemed to find your groove
and relax into it.
- Is that a fair assessment?
- Yeah.
I was quietly just sort of,
you know, doing stuff
and gathering information
and getting to know people.
And as the numbers got less,
it seemed the pressure was more on
and I rose to the pressure, I think.
I liked the pressure.
You really did. Absolutely.
Mat, day one, you're on the boat
heading down the river
and sitting there, in the Champion's
tribe, is Shane Gould.
- What did you think?
- I was impressed.
Um, I knew exactly who she was.
And, I mean, I think I was the next
oldest in the tribe
and, you know,
Shane's got 19 years on me.
So I was impressed with her courage
and her tenacity
and, yeah, you know, I loved it.
It was great.
Well, effectively Shane's been crowned
the champion of the Champions.
What have you learned from her
during Survivor?
Don't with Shane Gould.
Sorry, darling.
Shane, you never panicked, no matter
how much the pressure was on.
And you never became paranoid.
And these are two things that often
will unravel people's games.
And you never went there,
you held it together.
Here you are.
Congratulations. Well done.
Thank you.
Sharn, you were the only other one
to make it to the end of the game.
Five to four votes.
- It was pretty close.
- Yeah.
Let's take a look
at that final vote read.
Shane, you impressed me tonight, girl.
I wish I heard more about your game
when you were out there,
but you really proved yourself.
I'm just going for the underdog.
I think it's actually quite impressive.
You told me to put my weapon down,
but...
..it's my respect pistol.
Congrats on a great game.
You're more of a physical,
dominant player than Shane,
so my vote is going for you.
Unfortunately I can only award
one of you with my vote.
And, Sharn, I feel that you played
the superior game.
You don't win on loyalty but you win
on game play. You win on challenges.
You win on everything else.
You still have my vote.
I really value honesty
and I think Shane really showed that
tonight.
Her game is really endearing
and I'd be really proud if she won.
Shane, I'm voting for you.
Ooh!
I think you were the most honest
and loyal person
that I played with in this game.
Sharn, you made a mistake.
Your mistake of being disloyal to me
cost me the game.
But it also cost you my vote.
Shane, I hope you win. I love you.
Survivors don't run from challenges,
they accept them
and take them on board.
So for me...
..Shane is the Sole Survivor.
Wow, that's tough to watch.
Sharn, you missed out by one vote.
How does that feel?
Well, of course, you know,
it's disappointing, sure.
It's one vote between me
and $500,000, you know?
And I played my heart out out there.
But you know what?
I wouldn't change a thing because
I played the game true to myself.
I took Shane
because I respected her game
and she deserved to be sitting
there at the end with me.
And if that's the way the cookie
crumbles, so be it. I accept it.
But, you know, this jury
is different to the jury
that I deal with, Jonathan,
because the jury that I deal with
is an objective one.
These guys, they've all
got their emotions tied into it.
And that's the difference, yeah?
Well, you've kind of touched on
the $500,000 question
- I was gonna ask you.
- Yeah.
Do you regret not taking Brian
to the final two?
Look, I mean,
you can't do that in this game
because you've got to move forward.
And you can't go back and think,
"I wish I would've done something
differently."
You know, my purpose
and objective was to get Brian out.
He was gunning for me,
I was gunning for him.
I had that opportunity, so I took it.
OK, so you said that we can't play
that hypothetical game
but I can because I'm in charge.
- Of course.
- So...
I love it.
I want to play
the "What if..." game.
OK. Alright.
So let's say that you did take Brian
to the final two.
- Yep.
- And you put Shane on the jury.
Uh-huh.
Shane, who would you have voted for,
Sharn or Brian?
See?
I did share a bed... I did share
a bed with you for three nights.
You did. You did, yes.
Um... I probably would have
voted Sharn.
Um, because, um, yeah,
she'd, um, helped me
along through the game
and we had a bond.
But I would have voted
for second for you.
Thank you.
Sam...
..Sharn missed out by one vote.
But do you think
she played a great game?
Well, I did write her name down,
so obviously that's a yes.
Sharn had a more active game than Shane
and as the question I asked
sort of alluded to,
that was a big focus for me.
It's hard to make big moves
and then survive the fallout,
and Sharn managed to do that
and I was quite impressed.
Sharn, you played a hell of a game.
Well done.
Thanks.
Coming up, we'll take a look at some
of this year's epic challenges
and catch up with challenge beast
Lydia Lassila.
Later, we'll talk
to the Godfather about THAT tribal
that ended his game.
Don't go away.
Survivors ready? Go!
You've got this!
Zach takes him down.
Mat is all over him.
- Come on!
- You can be pretty brutal.
This game is on.
Throw me the axe! Throw the axe!
Contenders or the Champions,
who wants it the most?
Contenders want blood on this one.
Steve goes in!
I suppose you can call me
the Commando Killer.
Just like that, Zach is in.
Get off! Get off!
Mat's beaten Robbie every time
they go head to head.
Good job, Mat.
You got this, Rob.
Ooh, ooh!
My turn! Yes!
Australian Survivor's
most brutal challenge ever.
How much can you take on
before you panic?
Good job, Jenna, good job.
Oh, let go!
Oh, shit.
Oh, no, no!
Can we have the medic come in?
I wanna finish this.
OK, so just run
and go for broke.
Oh! She belly flops!
That's gonna leave a mark.
Oh, Monika misses again.
That was a hard hit.
Are you bleeding?
I don't know!
Come on, Mon, you've got this.
Monika, trying again.
She gets the rope.
Five-time Olympian.
Lydia's a machine.
Lydia's whipping across this.
Good job, Lyd.
Wow, huge effort from Lydia.
Lydia's been a powerhouse
in every challenge.
I think she's a terminator.
Champions are proving who they are!
Damien takes it out for the Champions!
Welcome back to the reunion show
Champions Versus Contenders.
Damien, we saw you win that first
immunity challenge for the Champions.
How did that feel?
It was amazing.
It was good to get out there
and just be able to...
I think contribute.
That was my fear
coming into the game, I was like,
"Alright, what if I can't contribute
to the team in any way?"
You know, like, every single person
on the team
has done something amazing
so it was great to be able to go out
and sort of compete alongside them.
You know, it's still intimidating,
'cause they're all awesome.
So you wanna kind of step up
when you get the ball. So...
I was breathing heavy when I threw
the first one, I'm not gonna lie.
It was a wide.
Lydia, we've never seen
such an incredible athlete
on Australian Survivor.
You were amazing to watch.
I don't know about that.
So earlier this year, you competed
in, what, is it your fifth Olympics?
- Yep.
- Why did you wanna play Survivor?
Um, it was a really good segue for me.
I was retiring from sport and wanted
to just dive into a new challenge
and what better way to do that,
to dive into Survivor?
Um, and it's just everything
about Survivor attracted me to it.
You know, the physical challenges
and I really loved
the survival aspect of it.
Um, and of course, there's
that social game, the manipulation
and seeing how far you can
advance yourself. It's tricky.
Robbie, at times, you seemed
transfixed by Lydia. What...?
Ooh!
I think we're all transfixed
by Robbie.
Oh, stop it.
What was it about her? What?
- Well...
- Those eyes.
What really sort of attracted me to
Lydia is her sort of mental courage
and mental stamina, you know?
Especially in that box court
challenge, you know,
when I was really struggling,
I was at my limit,
she said, "You've gotta dig deep,
you've gotta find your happy place,
"you've got so much more in you."
And just to hear that from someone
like that, you know,
it changed me as a person.
So I have so much respect for her
because she changed me,
for the better.
Ooh. Winning.
Lydia, how did it feel
when you watched the show back
and you're up on the pole,
fighting for your life,
and Shane Gould
is planning your blindside?
Oh, look, it wasn't surprising, really.
I knew Shane had that in her
as well, you know?
And sometimes in Survivor, you
have a bit of a stroke of bad luck.
You know, it rained for, like,
two minutes
and I slipped off the pole that
I wasn't gonna slip off, you know?
So, um, things change really quickly.
People kind of get a little jumpy.
Um, we had a really strong alliance,
one that probably didn't need to be
broken at the time that it was.
And perhaps that would have advanced,
you know, a lot more people's game.
You have unfinished business with
this game. Would you play again?
Oh, absolutely. I would.
I loved every minute of it.
Mat, one of my favourite rivalries
was between...
..you and... Robbie...
- Would you call that a rivalry?
- I knew you were gonna say that!
- What did you say?
- You and Robbie, I love that battle.
Remind me, what was the score.
- Oh...!
- Eight to one.
From the first time that I saw him
and it started,
I was terrified,
rocking into every challenge,
- 'cause he gave it everything and...
- He did.
..I guess just had
a bit of luck on my side.
Robbie, how was it,
going up against a rugby legend?
The very first challenge,
I looked at him and was like,
"I'm bigger than him,
I'm younger than him,
"I'm better looking than him..."
No, but I went into that, like,
"I've got this.
"You know,
I can get this first challenge."
And then... I underestimated him.
So all I could do was learn
from every single mistake
and try and get better and better
and try and beat him.
- Nice.
- It was good fun.
Monika, you're petrified of heights.
I mean, you belly flopped off it
almost every time and...
All! Every time!
One of them, you ended up, you know,
cutting your lip, bleeding,
but you never gave up.
That was probably the most
terrifying moment of my life,
thus far, it really was.
But as bad as it was,
I proved to myself
that I'm so much more courageous
than I ever gave myself credit for.
You know... Thank you.
Well done.
Well done for the courage.
Thank you.
Well, the point of Survivor
is to outwit, outplay and outlast
all the others,
and one guy thought he could do it
better than anyone else.
Let's take a look.
If you don't know me,
you've been living under a rock
for the last 10 years.
I'm King Russell.
And I'm the only king here, baby.
X...
..marks the spot.
It's amazing
how good I am at this game.
It's Christmas every day of the year
when Russell Hantz is here!
I'm gonna show you Aussies
how to play the game.
What?!
Oh, OK.
They is so stupid, they're
walking around with the devil
and don't even know he's there.
If we align like this right now,
we're going to the end together.
I'm playing with a bunch of dweebs.
There's no damn way
they putting my name down.
Russell? So Mr Texas,
there's no chance am I gonna be
in alliance with that man.
If anyone has a hidden immunity idol
and they wanna play it,
now would be the time to do so.
Russell, the tribe has spoken.
Well done, guys.
You've played the game three times
and never won, mate.
Maybe go home and review it
and try again.
Well, unfortunately,
our favourite villain, Russell,
has decided not to be here
but he is here in spirit.
Sharn, you called his bluff
and he went home wearing his idol.
- Mm.
- How does it feel, outplaying Russell?
- Feels great.
- It felt great in that moment.
You know, us girls, we kind of knew
that that was what he was gonna do,
he was out there, pretending,
and it was awesome.
And we kind of enjoyed that moment.
Only 'cause he'd been
big-noting himself, you know?
And especially because he had
the idol around his neck.
I mean, come on, you know?
That's confidence, over-confident.
Steve, if you could describe Russell
with one word, what would it be?
Idiot.
Well, going home with an idol
was a theme of this season.
After the break, we're gonna chat
with the Godfather
about the biggest blindside
in Australian Survivor history.
Don't go away.
Can they score?! Yes!
I've played at the top level
for my country
in rugby league and rugby union.
I've played against the biggest,
the best, the strongest, the fastest.
Why would I sign up for this?
Well, because it's the ultimate game.
Takes a shot.
Survivor is the toughest game
you could ever play.
As much as this game of Survivor
is physical in the challenges,
it's also social.
My goal is just to make sure that
I've got some really tight bonds
with the people in the tribe.
I want you to singe off my cheek hairs.
That's a big flame! You're going to
burn my eyelashes.
I feel like I've got a fairly decent
bit of control.
This is our life right now,
but it's a game.
So, as well as the social game,
it's important to bring people over.
The new alliance.
Yeah, Mat is fun in everything he does.
You've all got gifts.
He's charming and charismatic. He's
totally acting like the Godfather.
Right now, I guess you could say
I feel good.
I've got a hidden immunity idol
and I've got a good alliance,
it's rock solid.
It's now just about working out
how that alliance
turns into me being the Sole Survivor.
Welcome back.
Right now, we're talking to
the Godfather himself.
Mat, did you realise on the island
that you... they'd given you
that nickname?
No.
I mean, how do you think you got
the nickname of the Godfather?
Oh, just Benji being Benji.
He'd point his finger,
people going home.
Calling the shots the whole time.
I don't know, I like to
just talk to people.
Like, I'm a fun, social person and...
..I guess because
I was sort of talking a lot
and things seemed to happen based on
what our alliance were deciding,
people thought I was
pulling all the strings.
But I stand here and I'll say,
and Sharn will agree,
we would all just sit
and talk about it,
and I guess because I was delivering
the information,
it seemed to be, you know,
I was the Godfather, so...
- My son just got a Godfather T-shirt.
- Really?
Well, you've achieved so much
in your life.
Why did you want to play Survivor?
I remember watching the original series
when Richard Hatch won,
and I remember just looking at it,
thinking,
"Man, these guys have got no idea.
I want to get into it."
So, to get the chance, I just wanted
to get in there and test myself.
Yeah, it was a challenge,
but one that I thoroughly enjoyed.
Steve, you and Mat
quickly became buddies.
What was it about him
that you were drawn to?
God...
- Is it the eyes or...?
- Yeah, the eyes.
- And the moustache.
- Yeah, the mo'.
No, he's a chatterbox.
- And, um...
- Someone had to talk.
Well, Mat, you were
a physical powerhouse,
you had a great social game,
a strong alliance,
and an idol in your pocket,
but then it all went tits-up.
Let's have a look.
If anyone has a hidden immunity idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
I do have one I want to play.
But I'm playing it for Mat.
No, no, no.
Don't play it for Mat.
No, play it for you.
Play it for you.
It's going to go to a re-vote.
- Alright.
- It's your idol.
You play it
the way you want to play it.
OK...
Don't gamble your life, Sharn.
You're getting played.
I'll play it for...
..for myself.
Sharn, so I'm clear,
you're playing this for yourself?
- Yes.
What's going on?
- I...
- You're getting played.
It's going to be split.
16th person voted out of Australian
Survivor: Champions vs Contenders...
..Mat.
I think it's safe to say
that was the biggest blindside
we've seen on this show,
certainly the craziest.
Now, the whole country was in shock
when that happened.
I mean, I was in shock at the time.
What was going through your head?
When Benji piped up, it was probably
smarter than what he even thought
because not only did he...
When he said split vote, and
"Don't gamble your life" to Sharn,
I thought, "Well, they've obviously
thrown votes on Sharn."
Well, we've got four votes on Brian,
so I'll be right.
I still didn't even think
in my head, "Play my idol."
Like, it just...
I didn't even think...
I didn't even think about
pulling my idol out of the bag,
or Mo's idol, I should say,
out of the bag.
It was, um... I was just
trying to calculate stuff.
And I literally... like, it happens
that... in my mind, that quick.
Like, Sharn stood up and said
she was playing it for me,
and I'm sort of trying to calculate,
but by the time I looked around,
my name was being read out,
and I thought, "Oh, it's over."
But I think because Benji
was so aware of his play,
and it was coming undone,
he was quick to jump on it
when he saw it unfolding against him.
OK, I'm glad you brought that up.
Benji, it was a ballsy, brilliant move,
but had you planned for that, or
were you just thinking on your feet?
I 100% planned for that.
I knew it was going down that way
because Sharn and I
had talks on the beach earlier.
I disagree with that.
I don't think you knew,
because, you know what, I kind of
formed my view in tribal council.
I had... I was sitting there,
intending to play it for myself,
and then the way that the council
was going down,
I'm thinking, "Yep, this is
what's going to happen.
"I'm playing it for Matty."
So, I don't...
And I reckon, from what I saw
of Benji's reaction,
he thought, "Shit,
I've gotta do something here."
I think he used that word.
Maybe he considered it,
but he didn't know.
There's no way.
Like... Because like I said, I was
thinking that in tribal council,
literally at that time.
I thought, "Why would I, you know,
do this?
"Why would I play it for myself
when I can play it for Mat,
"and then, you know,
ultimately save Mat."
But then when Benji piped up,
I thought,
"OK, maybe there's something
I don't know about,
"it could go to a re-vote,"
and there would have been, you know,
a completely different story.
There's so many things...
On that point too, Sharn,
I was flipping, 100%.
I'd made my mind up, "I wanna
take down this Champion alliance,"
which was killing us the whole game.
I had an idol in my pocket
and I knew the votes
were landing on Brian.
If you played that for Mat,
I'd play my idol for Brian
and then you go home.
Well, Survivor really is
about key moments,
and I think it's fair to say, Mat,
that you had quite a few.
So, not getting rid of Brian
when you had a chance,
good or bad decision?
Yeah, it's probably a move
I regret a little, that one.
Nah, don't worry about it.
Keeping Benji over Sam.
Good or bad decision?
Um, I don't think... I don't think
that was a bad decision
because I know what Sam was plotting.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
It was either going to be Benji
or me going after Mat next.
- Yeah.
- I got the honours.
Yeah, well, screw you.
Well, to finish up, what was the
hardest part of the game for you?
It was probably that final vote.
Looking at Shane and Sharn,
you know, both my alliance,
you know, I just had to make
a logical decision.
Would have been a lot easier
if she'd taken Brian.
For me, that is.
Maybe not for others.
I'm just getting whacked everywhere,
aren't I?
Still love you.
We love you, Grubby.
Alright. Well, after the break,
we talk to the guy
that took down the Godfather.
And later, we catch up
with power couple Shonella.
Stick around.
I have told many lies
in this game to many people.
They're saying Anita tonight
and Shonee next.
It's important for us
to know who we're playing with.
That's the lie that sent me to Exile.
I didn't make anything up.
You never said that...
You said that you were
targeting those three...
Benji, don't stand here
and lie to my face, bro.
So, the curtain has been drawn back
and everyone has seen me
holding the strings.
I have told, like, one lie.
So, I'm not actually
a graphic designer.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah, I'm not.
I run a business.
It made, like,
over $1 million last year.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah.
Benji told me he's a millionaire.
Benji is sneaky as.
I don't think that's his real accent.
I got your back out here.
- It's Sharnji. Sharnji.
- Sharnji to the end.
Sharnji to the endji. Totally.
That's our motto.
- What do you mean, you haven't lied?
- Not much.
- Not that much.
- Well, some.
Wait, let me think about it.
Maybe I have.
Welcome back to the
Australian Survivor Reunion Show.
Shane has just won
half a million dollars.
She says she played
with loyalty and honesty,
a completely different approach
to this man here, Benji.
Roughly how many lies do you think
you told during this game?
- Um...
- Don't lie.
Lost count on day two.
Robbie says we didn't tell
that many but actually,
what I wanted to do is...
There's a guy who thinks he's
the biggest villain of all time
and he got voted out first on
his tribe and doesn't even show up.
So I wanted to just take his hat
and put it where it belongs.
Because he's not the greatest.
I was gonna do that.
But to answer your question,
I told a lot of lies out there.
- A lot?
- A lot.
I don't know
if I told the truth at any one time.
Well, look, in a game where you need
to vote someone out
every second night,
deception is obviously key,
and you were a master at it.
Was that a plan coming in?
Yeah, when you get the opportunity
to play Survivor, I mean,
so many people try out for this
and we're all so appreciative
we got on.
Like, you've got to play hard,
you've got to go out there,
you've got to lie, you've got
to deceive, you've got to have fun.
You've just got to give 100% at it.
So when I got the opportunity,
I'm like,
"Yeah, I'm gonna play it big,"
because, like, I don't want to get
dragged to the end by the Godfather.
I want to play my own game
and set my own rules
like I do with my own life.
Well, you lied to get rid of Tegan,
but she came back.
Were you nervous about that?
I was very nervous, yeah.
Tegan came back really scary.
She came back with a vengeance.
And you just revealed all of my and
Robbie's plans, and Zach's plans,
so that was very nerve-racking.
But we put an end to that.
Tegan, how did you feel
knowing that your game was
turned upside-down by a lie?
It was really shocking to me
because I just didn't think
that Benji had it in him.
So when Anita came to Exile and
told me what had happened, I just...
I was so shocked. You know,
it was written all over my face.
At tribal council, I had no idea
that I was gonna be the person
getting sent home that night.
Well, speaking of lies, there was
one that was never uncovered.
Jackie.
Speed Cuber.
Yeah, I actually never told
a single person
and, you know, I went in there
to play Survivor and...
..you know...
I wasn't there to go camping.
I wasn't there to make friends.
I wasn't there to climb walls.
I was there to play Survivor.
Like, yeah.
And unfortunately, you know,
I went home early.
But I just never wanted to go in there
and just hang on to someone
and just try
and get to the end that way.
Benji, there was another secret
that was never uncovered.
For you, Survivor is a family affair.
- Anneliese... Where are you?
- Hey.
Anneliese from season two
is your sister.
Yeah, she is.
She's my little sister.
- Hey, Ben.
- Hey, how are you going?
Yeah, she is my little sis.
She went out and played
a hell of a game out there
and she lasted 38 days
and I went out and played
a hell of a game and lasted 39 days.
Yeah, but, Benji, at least Anneliese
played her idol before she went home.
Thank you!
Speaking of your idol,
let's take a look at that scene
that we will never forget.
I'm going.
That's delicious.
What's this?
Goddamn, it's a clue.
I'm gonna try and cover it.
Yes.
So good, man.
Building up a sweat.
I'm slowing down.
Mm!
This is not my finest moment.
OK, hands up if that was the grossest
thing you've ever seen?
No, I've seen grosser.
- You didn't experience, Jono.
- What?
- Me and him had to experience that.
- I was getting to that.
- OK.
- Both you guys turned up afterwards.
What did you think
when you watch that back?
I've got two dogs and two kids at home.
And they've got better table manners
than Benji, so...
Look, 23 days into the game,
we're all still pretty hungry.
So, I mean, even if
I had have seen him eat like that,
I probably... I still would have
went in and had nachos.
But everyone that's come up to me
since coming home,
they've asked me
if I've eaten nachos again.
I don't think I could ever eat
nachos without him on my mind.
I certainly can't eat nachos again.
Coming up after the break, we'll chat
to the power couple Shonella.
And later, we'll talk to
the most controversial player
we've ever had.
Don't go away.
Eww!
- What was that?
- My God.
A bug just flew so close to my ear.
Fenella and I have a special ability
to find cracks
and just float our way to the top.
Game on, molls.
We laugh at the same things
and, yeah, she's my bestie.
Yay.
Ah, slipped through
the cracks once again.
I think the biggest topic is...
It's very obvious that Shonee and
Fenella are a really tight pair.
We've started calling them Shonella.
Because they are a power couple.
Shane, are there
any tight two alliances?
There's a Shonella.
Shonella?
- Is that, like, a perfume.
- Sounds expensive.
Luxurious.
- You've got a necklace on, too.
- I'll clap to that.
Welcome back to
the Australian Survivor Reunion Show.
We're talking to Shonella,
this year's unlikely power couple.
Unlikely? What do you mean, mate?
Match made in heaven.
Shonee, what was it about Fenella
that you found irresistible?
Well, I came for the rice...
I didn't come for the rice,
I came for the money,
and stayed for the rice and this lady.
Beautiful.
I ate a termite
and it turned into love.
When you were called out as a power
couple, was that a surprise to you?
Not at all.
We were like,
"Why did it take people 40 days
"to realise
that we are very powerful?"
No. I think it was 45, wasn't it?
- No. It didn't last that long.
- Oh. 44.
Well, back on day one
when you saw the Champions walk in,
what were you thinking?
Shane was the only one I knew.
I did a project on her in Year 5.
And I think I got an A.
Well, Mat, I mean, Shonella,
they had a great social game.
Do you think
people underestimated them?
Oh, I certainly didn't.
I knew that they were powerful
and I knew that they were two votes,
that they were not separating,
they were dangerous.
Well, two is a strong number
in this game,
but three is even stronger.
And there was one guy
that fit right in with the Shonella.
Oh, boy.
I'm going to play at Survivor
like I play football.
Survivors, ready? Go!
Oh, Brian pushes Heath to the side.
Too easy.
He puts it in the square and Brian
takes it out for the Champions.
Oh, my God, are you kidding me?
Grubby, you've got to
get that checked out, man.
No-one needs to see that.
Jesus.
King Grub.
I don't know if
I like to take that mantle.
I mean, I'll take the Grub part of it.
You look good, Grubby.
They could have probably
found worser nicknames.
I've probably had worse in my time
at high school and football.
But I'll take it.
- Who wants to see the white whale?
- Me. Please.
The girls keep using it,
that means they
actually care about you.
- Grubby bum.
- What?! Oh, my God.
Brian, I think I've been scarred for
life after seeing that last image.
You knew there was a camera rolling
on you, right?
I knew there was numerous cameras.
But I had to wash.
You won four
individual immunity challenges,
a car, and you came third.
Are you happy with the way you played?
Yeah. You look at the series now,
you think, hindsight,
"If I did this differently,
"if I did that differently..."
But do I get fitter?
Do I learn how to make fire
before I come into Survivor? Yes.
Maybe I could have changed things
but then you just don't know
what else could have changed
in that scenario.
There might have been
a different person,
a different player in this game,
so to come in as raw as I did,
to come third
from the position I was in,
I'm definitely very happy
with what I've achieved.
Were there similarities
between how you played Survivor
- and how you played footy?
- Dirty.
Dirty? Yeah. I heard...
Nah. I probably wasn't the most
professional footballer
when I played the game.
I used to like to have a good time.
But playing team sport
I knew how to get a team together
and if there's a way
that we can manipulate the game,
not classified as cheating,
- if I can bend the rules somehow...
- Being grubby.
..I would do that
as much as possible.
Well, Australia was surprised
when you voted out Steve
when he was Dead Man Walking.
What was the logic behind that?
In that position, yes, he hadn't
gone very well in challenges,
but I knew
when it comes to the last challenge,
it's always very demanding.
So if you're going to take someone
like Steve to the final three,
you're going to be up against it.
So, hindsight, I probably
should have taken Sharn out.
Um...
- Yeah.
You look back at it
and you've made mistakes.
Was that one of them?
Maybe. Maybe not. I don't know.
Mate, there's no hard feelings
on my behalf for anyone here.
I think it was... it's amazing.
And it's amazing to sit here with
everybody tonight and reminisce.
I think a lot of us here
would put our hand up and say
we'd go back there in a heartbeat.
After the break, we'll talk to Zach,
the most controversial player
we've ever had.
Yeah...
Zach has it! And Zach
takes it for the Contenders.
Zach has him on the edge.
And that's it!
#CommandoKiller.
Look at all that muscle out there!
Why don't you puff your chest
a little more, mate?
You should borrow my sports bra.
I think it is highly possible that a
woman could beat me in a challenge.
But that all depends on what it is.
If it's physical strength,
girl, no chance.
OK. But if we're looking
at, maybe, like,
a dishwashing challenge
or maybe a sewing challenge,
I might be in trouble.
We've got girls
that just... they suck.
We've got graphic designers and mums
and whatever the hell it is Paige does.
The plan is from here
is just to cut out
all the rest of the girls
and just systematically wipe them out.
"Oh, my God.
"I can't believe
you guys voted for me."
Eighth person voted out
Champions Versus Contenders...
..Zach.
Just a washed-up gladiator
that ended up on the wrong beach.
Welcome back to the Reunion Show.
Now, we've gotta talk about the man
who caused so much discussion
on the beach and in the lounge rooms
around the country.
Zach.
Um...
Dude, what is it that you have
against the female Contenders?
I didn't have anything
against the female contestants.
You've taken it the absolute wrong way.
Serious. No, you don't know.
I mean, the thing is I was just
getting so frustrated at that stage.
I mean, we were just losing
challenge after challenge
after challenge, and from what I...
I mean, the Champions' girls
were just so bad ass.
You know, you have a look at them,
we've got Olympic gold medallists
and, you know, just absolute killers.
So, you know,
they were whooping our women.
Whoopin' 'em.
You've got to remember,
Zach's pumping a lot of meat.
He's got bigger boobs than half of
us girls on the tribe to start with.
So, you know, he can sit there and
talk about dishwasher challenges,
but maybe if he tried one,
he'd be sitting down there
instead of up here, so...
Whoo...
Zach, at any point, did you think,
you know,
"Maybe I should just shut up"?
Look. Sure.
I think a couple of times there
I thought maybe
I should just keep my mouth shut.
But there's only so much stupidity
you can listen to before I just...
Fenella, what do you say to that?
- Um... Look...
- Say it.
Everyone's speechless.
I don't even know.
Look, Zach is his own person.
But at the end of the day I'm so
glad Zach came into this tribe
because it meant
that I could be sitting where I am
and he's where he is.
OK. Before we finish up, Lydia,
you've achieved so much in your
career, where does Survivor rank?
Oh, it's one of the best experiences
probably of my life.
It's been incredible.
- Mat, would you do it again?
- Ah, tomorrow.
Moana, how would you sum up
your experience on Survivor?
It was probably the best experience
of my life.
Like, same as Lyds, I'd absolutely
do it again. It was pretty awesome.
Benji, any tips for future players?
If you find one of these things, or
the necklace, you've got to play it.
Apparently it saves you out there.
So, if you think you have what it takes
to win the greatest game on earth,
casting is now open for the next
season of Australian Survivor.
And next year, it could be you up here.
Contenders, Champions, thank you
for a brilliant season. Well done.
So, after 50 days and 24 people,
we have one Survivor.
Goodnight.